welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive in this video we're going to be
Kdenlive在这段视频中我们将成为
using kitten live to do the green-screen
用小猫LIVE做绿屏
chroma key effect so we'll take a blue
色度键效果 所以我们将使用蓝色
background or a green background screen
背景或绿色背景屏幕
and make it transparent and overlay it
并使其透明并覆盖它
over top of another video so first of
在另一个视频之上 所以第一个
all we need to get some green screen
我们所需要的只是得到一些绿色屏幕
footage so if you want to follow along
如果你想跟上的话
or maybe you already have your own but
或许你已经有了自己的但是
if you don't you can go to pixabay.com
如果你没有 你可以去Pixabay.com
we can get some free green screen
我们可以得到一些免费的绿色屏幕
footage just search under videos and
只需在视频下搜索视频和
search a green screen and then we'll
搜索绿色屏幕 然后我们将
find the nice thing so we'll get this
找到最好的东西 这样我们就能得到这个
like that this butterfly how about yeah
就像这样 这只蝴蝶怎么样？
this is to butterfly so so nice short
这是对蝴蝶如此美好的简短
video perfect for us this is by Z vector
视频非常适合我们 这是Z向量
so appreciate that user sharing this
所以非常感谢用户分享这一点
with us creative commons 0 free for
与我们的知识共享0免费
personal and commercial use so we'll
个人和商业用途 所以我们将
download this 1920 by 1080 and yeah well
下载这个1920到1080年的版本 好的
you said is our file so first of all and
你说这是我们的档案 所以首先
I have another file that we've used in
我有另一个文件 我们在
the past so I'm gonna go to my downloads
过去 所以我要去我的下载
folder actually let's just do well do is
实际上让我们做好的文件夹是
this beach one that we've been using
我们一直在用的这个海滩
it's kind of fun you know drag in this
这很有趣 你知道的 把这件事扯进来
green screen of the butterfly so we take
蝴蝶的绿色屏幕 所以我们带着
our beach scene first whatever we want
我们的海滩场景首先是我们想要的
to have be our our background video or
作为我们的背景视频或
image and then our green screen we want
图像 然后是我们想要的绿色屏幕
to do on top of it and so I'm going to
在上面做的事情 所以我要
zoom in here on the timeline so I can
放大这里的时间线 这样我就可以
see look the better what's going on I'm
看 看得越好 发生了什么 我是
going to come to the end of this beach
会来到这片海滩的尽头
scene and resize it down to the length
场景并将其大小调整到长度
of this video clip of the butterfly
这只蝴蝶的视频片段
perfect so now and then I'll zoom in
太完美了 所以我会不时地放大
even more on the timeline so we can
更多的时间线上 这样我们就可以
really get a good idea for what's
真正对什么有个好主意
happening here perfect so now if we play
在这里发生完美的事情 所以现在如果我们玩
this it just shows the butterfly against
这只是蝴蝶对着它的表现
a green screen but underneath it's
一个绿色的屏幕 但它下面是
playing the video of the beach of the
播放海滨录像带
coastline we just can't see it because
我们就是看不到海岸线 因为
the green screen is you know filling up
绿色的屏幕正在填满你知道的
the whole screen so we need to make that
整个屏幕 所以我们需要制作
green go away to do that we use the
要做到这一点 我们使用了
chroma key so we can just start typing
色度键 这样我们就可以开始打字了
in might even be under color huh yeah
In甚至可能被涂上了颜色哈是的
chroma hold but come up here just type
色度保持 但到这里来只需打字
in
在……里面
chromakey it's always under alpha
色键它总是在Alpha下
manipulation so we want to find
所以我们想要找出
chromakey and we'll just drag chromakey
色键 我们只需拖动色键
over top of the video that has the green
在带有绿色的视频上方
screen in it and it comes up with some
在它的屏幕上 它会出现一些
options over here under properties so
选项在此处的属性下 因此
right now it's saying what is the color
现在它说的是什么颜色
key it's saying it's blue right now we
它说它现在是蓝色的 我们
can try and like set it to green but
我可以试着把它设置成绿色 但是
it's not really gonna work we need to
它不会真的起作用 我们需要
choose the exact color so to do that we
选择正确的颜色 以便我们做到这一点
use this color picker and we click pick
使用此颜色选择器 然后我们单击Pick
a color and then click on the color we
一种颜色 然后点击我们想要的颜色
want and instantly it goes to full green
想要 立刻就变成了满满的绿色
now this screen was if we turn this off
现在这个屏幕是如果我们把它关掉
look at this it's not really a screen
看这个 这不是一个真正的屏幕
this is a 3d rendered so it's already a
这是一个3D渲染 所以它已经是一个
perfect green color if you have a real
完美的绿色 如果你有一个真正的
green screen you're gonna have some
绿屏 你会有一些
you're gonna have trouble keying it
你在按键时会有困难
correctly possibly and so you can change
可能是正确的 所以你可以改变
this variance I'll turn this back on you
这个差异 我会把这个放回你头上
get this variance here the in change and
把这个变化放在这里 然后
see so now parts of the butterfly or
现在看到的是蝴蝶的一部分或
evinced going transparent so you can
表示变得透明这样你就可以
change this variance here to see you
在此更改此方差即可看到您
know to get yours to work properly but
知道要让你的电脑正常工作 但是
ours worked really good because it's a
我们的工作非常好 因为它是一种
3d rendered green screen all right now
3D渲染的绿色屏幕现在就可以了
so if we play this we'll see it'll play
所以如果我们玩这个 我们就会看到它会播放
the video of the background and it's
背景的视频和它
butterflies like we flying around but
像我们一样飞来飞去的蝴蝶
it's huge maybe we want to change it so
它是巨大的 也许我们想要改变它
just remember we can change if we go to
只要记住 我们可以改变 如果我们去
our effects and then we get rid of this
我们的影响 然后我们处理掉这个
under crop and transform we can just
在裁剪和变换下 我们只需
apply a transform to this in addition to
除了对此应用变换外 还应对其应用变换
the green screen we can apply a
我们可以将绿色屏幕应用于
transform and we can just transform it
改变 我们就可以改变它
go to the middle so we can kind of see
到中间去 这样我们就能看到
and then we can just transform it down -
然后我们就可以把它向下转换-
yeah about here so we can have this
是的 大约在这里 这样我们就可以有这个了
butterfly just flying along maybe we'll
蝴蝶在飞翔 也许我们会
put it over here if we click play it'll
把它放在这里 如果我们点击播放它将
just stay that size the whole time and
一直保持这个尺寸 然后
kind of fly ahead doing its thing
有点像飞在前面做自己的事情
yeah that's how I want to do look we can
是的 这就是我想要做的 看起来我们可以
change the rotation of it to go back to
将其旋转更改为返回到
the middle so we can actually change the
中间部分 因此我们可以实际更改
rotation of the butterfly too so that it
旋转的蝴蝶太多了 让它
looks like it's flying more with the
看起来它飞得更多了
angle of the camera a little bit maybe
相机的角度可能会有点小
anyway so that is it that is as simple
不管怎样 就这么简单吗？
as it is using green screen
因为它使用的是绿色屏幕
and again you'll learn you know if
再一次 你会知道如果你知道
you're just getting into green screen
你才刚刚进入绿屏
the setup of your green screen if you're
设置您的绿屏 如果您
filming your own getting your lighting
拍摄你自己的灯光
perfect is going to make your life a lot
完美会让你的生活变得更美好
easier than trying to key it and change
比试图键入并更改它更容易
it around in the software yeah hope you
它在软件里到处都是 希望你
found this video informative that's how
我觉得这段视频很有见地 就是这样
you'd green screen if you had a blue
如果你有一个蓝色的屏幕 你会是绿屏
screen you could change you want to
屏幕 你可以改变你想要的
change it manually the color like this
手动更改颜色 如下所示
you always want to click on this dot and
你总是想点击这个点 然后
then left click and select your screen
然后左键单击并选择您的屏幕
yeah thanks for watching join me in the
是啊 感谢收看和我一起参加
next video we'll see you then
下一个视频我们到时见